It's not just a game anymore.
Clue is a comedy, thriller, crime film directed by Jonathan Lynn.
Clue finds six colorful dinner guests gathered at the mansion of their host, Mr.
Boddy -- who turns up dead after his secret is
exposed: He was blackmailing all of them.
With the killer among them, the guests and Boddy's chatty butler
must suss out the culprit before the body count rises.
Wadsworth, played by Tim Curry.
Mrs. Peacock, played by Eileen Brennan.
Mrs. White, played by Madeline Kahn.
Professor Plum, played by Christopher Lloyd.
Mr. Green, played by Michael McKean.
Colonel Mustard, played by Martin Mull.
Clue is a 1985 American black comedy mystery film based on the
board game Clue (Cluedo outside North America).
It was written and directed by Jonathan Lynn, who
co-wrote the story with John Landis.
It features an ensemble cast, including Eileen Brennan, Tim Curry, Madeline Kahn,
Christopher Lloyd, Michael McKean, Martin Mull, and Lesley Ann Warren.
The film has multiple different endings.
Each of three possibilities were screened at different
theaters, and home media releases include all of them.
The film initially received mixed reviews and performed poorly at the box office, grossing $15 million in
the United States against a budget of $15 million, but later developed a cult following.
The film explores themes of blackmail, butler, board game, mansion, whodunit.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending and intense.